A Guide to Arean Stage Production Correspondence
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena Stage Production Correspondence 1962-1997
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University Libraries
Arena 006
18 containers comprising 9.1 cubic feet (13.65 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated to George Mason University Libraries by Arena Stage in the fall of 2000
Biographical Information
Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. One of the first not-for-profit theaters in the United States as well as a pioneer of the regional theater movement the Arena Stage was the first regional theater to transfer a production to Broadway, the first invited by the U.S. State Department to tour behind the Iron Curtain and the first to receive a Tony Award. Co-founded in 1950 by Edward Mangum a teacher from the George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler one of his students, Arena Stage was opened in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Deriving it's name from the idea of "theater in the round," Arena Stage became one of the first resident theaters in the United States, beginning with a company of only eight actors. Today, Arena performs to over 250,000 patrons during a September to June season and employs nearly 200 theater professionals and craft persons, who are responsible for all the costumes and scenery seen on stage. Many now- famous actors took part in Arena Stage productions during the early part of their careers. Some of them include Robert Prosky, Morgan Freeman, Dianne Weist, James Earl Jones, Kevin Kline, Christopher Guest, Yeardly Smith and Samuel L. Jackson. Donated to George Mason University in fall of 2000, the Arena Stage Collection contains materials spanning the theater's 50 year history including production notebooks, photographs, playbills, scrapbooks, scripts and handwritten correspondence and other production materials.
Scope and Content
This series includes correspondence and other miscellaneous materials regarding Arena Stage productions and covers the years 1962-1997.
Arrangement
by production title/subject
Contents List
- Arena Stage Collection, Production Correspondence
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1962 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1963 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1964 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1965 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1966 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1967 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, 1968 (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group: misc. materials (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group reports, 1960's (Box Box 1)
  - Theater Communications Group correspondence, travel (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation travel and expense reports (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation" program for scenic design (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: misc. news clippings (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: playwrights program (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: program for poets and fiction writers (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: new playwrights program (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: interns (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: reports (Box Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation: plans (Box Box 1)
  - "Leonce and Lena", 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Arturo Ui": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Three Men on a Horse": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Tom": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Inherit the Wind": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Our Town": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Krapp's Last Tape / Not I": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - The Bread and Puppet Theater (Box Box 2)
  - National and Little Theater of the Deaf (Box Box 2)
  - misc. 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Jump at the Sun": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Death of a Salesman": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Death of a Salesman":1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Who's Afraid of Virginia Wolf": 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "Julius Caesar": 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "The last meeting of the Knights of the White Magnolia": 1974 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Dybbuk": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Accent of Mt. Fuji": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Sizwe Banzi / The Island": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Oba Koso": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - Russia Royalties; 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - Associated Producers Inc., 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - director and designer contracts; 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. play correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - " A Long Days Journey into Night": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Enemy of the People": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Once in a Lifetime": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Charles Dickens w/ Emlyn Williams":1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "The Tot Family": 1976 (Box Box 2)
  - "Heartbreak House": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Waiting for Godot": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Waiting for Godot": 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - workshop productions: 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "Dandelion Wine": 1976 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. play correspondence: 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - Samuel French Inc., play correspondence: 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. play correspondence: 1975 (Box Box 2)
  - "A History of the American Film": 1980 (Box Box 2)
  - "Catsplay": 1977 (Box Box 2)
  - "Catsplay": 1979 (Box Box 2)
  - "Streamers" :1977 (Box Box 2)
  - "That Time / Play / Footfalls": 1976 (Box Box 2)
  - "Dylan Thomas w/ Emlyn Williams": 1976 (Box Box 2)
  - "Forever Yours Marie-Lou": 1977 (Box Box 2)
  - "First the Good News": 1977 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. plays and special events: 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - special events, 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - designer/director contracts, 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - designer/director contracts: 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. plays 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - " In the Process": 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - Samuel French Inc., 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - Israel Festival: 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - Holland Festival: 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - misc. correspondence "A" (Box Box 3)
  - Brett Adams Ltd., 1980-1985 (Box Box 3)
  - Am-Rus Literary Agency; 1980-1985 (Box Box 3)
  - Authors and Artists Management, London 1980 (Box Box 3)
  - Emanuel Azenburg, 1980 (Box Box 3)
  - Manhattan Theater Club, 1979-1984 (Box Box 3)
  - George Borchardt, 1984 (Box Box 3)
  - Lois Berman, 1979-1986 (Box Box 3)
  - Bertha Case, 1979-1984 (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "B" (Box Box 3)
  - Brandt and Brandt Dramatic Dept. Inc. (Box Box 3)
  - Rosica Colin Ltd. (Box Box 3)
  - Curtis-Brown Agency (Box Box 3)
  - Judy Daish Assoc. (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "D" (Box Box 3)
  - Ann Elmo Agency (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "E" (Box Box 3)
  - Samuek French Ltd. (Box Box 3)
  - Fraser and Dunlop (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "F" (Box Box 3)
  - Robert A. Freedman (Box Box 3)
  - Eric Class Ltd. (Box Box 3)
  - Great Northern Agency (Box Box 3)
  - Graham Agency (Box Box 3)
  - Goodwin Assoc. (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "G" (Box Box 3)
  - Scott Hudson Inc. (Box Box 3)
  - Hesseltine/Baker (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "H" (Box Box 3)
  - I.C.M. (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "I-J" (Box Box 3)
  - Bertha Klausner (Box Box 3)
  - Lucy Kroll (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "K" (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "L" (Box Box 3)
  - Joyce P. Ketay (Box Box 3)
  - The Lantz Office (Box Box 3)
  - Floria Lasky (Box Box 3)
  - Sheila Lemon (Box Box 3)
  - misc correspondence "M" (Box Box 3)
  - William Morris (Box Box 3)
  - Mary McAllister (Box Box 3)
  - Elizabeth Marton (Box Box 3)
  - Michael Imison (Box Box 3)
  - Helen Merrill (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "N" (Box Box 3)
  - Ellen Neuwald (Box Box 3)
  - O'Neill Center (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "O" (Box Box 3)
  - Rosenstone/Wender (Box Box 3)
  - Margaret Ramsay (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "P and Q" (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "R" (Box Box 3)
  - Howard Rosenstone (Box Box 3)
  - Barbara Rhodes (Box Box 3)
  - Shukat Co., Ltd. (Box Box 3)
  - Susan Schulman (Box Box 3)
  - Jonathan Sand (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "S" (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "T" (Box Box 3)
  - Russell Vandernbroucke (Box Box 3)
  - Ubu (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "U-V" (Box Box 3)
  - Audrey Wood (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "W" (Box Box 3)
  - misc. correspondence "W,Y,Z" (Box Box 3)
  - 1993-1994 fellows (Box Box 4)
  - fellows project 1994, "Voices in the Threshold" (Box Box 4)
  - 1994-1995 fellows program (Box Box 4)
  - fellows, 1995-1996 (Box Box 4)
  - fellows 1996-1997 (Box Box 4)
  - retreat planning folder (Box Box 4)
  - leadership transition (Box Box 4)
  - Shaunung Doug (Box Box 4)
  - senior staff 1991 (Box Box 4)
  - Arts on Education 1994-1995 (Box Box 4)
  - Arts in Education 1995-1996 (Box Box 4)
  - 2K playwrights festival 1997 (Box Box 4)
  - Play Quest (Box Box 4)
  - Play Quest 1993-1994 (Box Box 4)
  - Play Quest 1994-1995 (Box Box 4)
  - Play Quest 1995-1996 (Box Box 4)
  - Molly Sweeney (Box Box 4)
  - A month in the Country (Box Box 4)
  - Mrs. Klein (Box Box 4)
  - The Odyssey (Box Box 4)
  - Of Thee I Sing (Box Box 4)
  - A Perfect Ganesh (Box Box 4)
  - The Plough and the Stars (Box Box 4)
  - The Price (Box Box 4)
  - Kiss me Kate (Box Box 4)
  - The Little Prince (Box Box 4)
  - Long Days Journey into Night (Box Box 4)
  - Love Letters Benefit (Box Box 4)
  - Lovers and Executioners (Box Box 4)
  - Matchmaker (Box Box 4)
  - Misalliance (Box Box 4)
  - She Miser (Box Box 4)
  - The House of Martin Guerre (Box Box 4)
  - Hysteria (Box Box 4)
  - I Am a Man (Box Box 4)
  - I'd Rather be Right (Box Box 4)
  - In the Deep Hearts Core (Box Box 4)
  - Ain't Nothin but the Blues (Box Box 4)
  - It's the Truth (if you think it is) (Box Box 4)
  - Jar the Floor (Box Box 4)
  - Jelly Roll (Box Box 4)
  - John Gabriel Borkman (Box Box 4)
  - Journey to the West (Box Box 4)
  - June Moon (Box Box 4)
  - general correspondence "A" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "B", 1 of 2 (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "B", 2 of 3 (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "C" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "D", 1 of 2 (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "D", 2 of 2 (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "E" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "F" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "G" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "H" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "I-J" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "K" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "L" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "M" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "N" (Box Box 5)
  - General correspondence "O" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "P-Q" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "R" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "S" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "T" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "U-V" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "W" (Box Box 5)
  - general correspondence "X,Y,,Z" (Box Box 5)
  - contribution information 1980-1981 (Box Box 6)
  - affirmative action and misc. items (Box Box 6)
  - D.C. public schools contract info (Box Box 6)
  - Youth Awarness Program (Box Box 6)
  - community service project reconciliations 1988-1989 (Box Box 6)
  - community service project 1988-1989 (Box Box 6)
  - Community service project 1988-1989 (Box Box 6)
  - community service project 1987-1988 (Box Box 6)
  - community service proposal 1987-1988 (Box Box 6)
  - community service project general info (Box Box 6)
  - misc. bills (Box Box 6)
  - transcript of Robert Alexander at American University (Box Box 6A)
  - Living Stage / U. of Michigan (Box Box 6A)
  - Van American Foundation (Box Box 6A)
  - City Museum Project 1979 (Box Box 6A)
  - Internships (Box Box 6A)
  - Tiber Island (Box Box 6A)
  - Fedapt resources (Box Box 6A)
  - rewrites (Box Box 6A)
  - Space P.R. (Box Box 6A)
  - Notes (Box Box 6A)
  - correspondence, Cathy Irwin (Box Box 6A)
  - budget (Box Box 6A)
  - DOE proposal draft 1988 (Box Box 7)
  - addresses of supporters (Box Box 7)
  - Ballou Evaluation 1982-1983 (Box Box 7)
  - Audit (Box Box 7)
  - brown bag lunch programs (Box Box 7)
  - relationships (Box Box 7)
  - young audience (Box Box 7)
  - peace (Box Box 7)
  - bob's papers on self (Box Box 7)
  - RAD (Box Box 7)
  - D.C. humanities (Box Box 8)
  - suggestions (Box Box 8)
  - current addresses (Box Box 8)
  - misc. Living Stage info (Box Box 8)
  - Living Stage info (Box Box 8)
  - associate letter (Box Box 8)
  - special proposal (Box Box 8)
  - Frank Hodsoll, NEA (Box Box 8)
  - American Arts Alliance (Box Box 8)
  - TCG annual report (Box Box 8)
  - Nabil Sawelka (Box Box 8)
  - Elspeth Udvarhelyi (Box Box 8)
  - misc. correspondence (Box Box 8)
  - DOE proposal 1988 (Box Box 8)
  - DOE proposal draft 1988 (Box Box 8)
  - Susan and Michael Samuels (Box Box 9)
  - fund raising (Box Box 9)
  - Ballou H.S. evaluation (Box Box 9)
  - ASP evaluation 1983-1984 (Box Box 9)
  - D.C. jail evaluation for women 1983-1984 (Box Box 9)
  - D.C. jail evaluations 1982-1983 (Box Box 9)
  - evaluations 1982-1983 (Box Box 9)
  - evaluations 1982-1983 (Box Box 9)
  - evaluations 1982-1983 (Box Box 9)
  - Evaluations 1982-1983 (Box Box 9)
  - Learning Stage Arena (Box Box 9)
  - DOE 1988 appendix (Box Box 9)
  - DOE proposals 1988 (Box Box 9)
  - contact sheets, 1 of 3 (Box Box 10)
  - contact sheets, 2 of 3 (Box Box 10)
  - contact sheets, 3 of 3 (Box Box 10)
  - misc. memos and correspondence, July/December 1989 (Box Box 10)
  - misc. memos and correspondence, April - June 1989 (Box Box 10)
  - Reading file Jan. - March 1989 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - Oct. - Dec. 1988 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - July-Sept. 1988 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - April - June 1988 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - March 1988 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - Jan. - Feb.1988 (Box Box 11)
  - reading file - Sept. - Dec. 1987 (Box Box 11)
  - Staff Meeting minutes 1980-1983 (Box Box 12)
  - staff meeting minutes 1983-1985 (Box Box 12)
  - staff meeting minutes 1986-1989 (Box Box 12)
  - contact sheets - 1970's (Box Box 12)
  - reading files special events (Box Box 13)
  - reading files / special events (Box Box 13)
  - reading files / special events (Box Box 13)
  - reading files / special events (Box Box 13)
  - 2nd copy (Box Box 13)
  - staff meeting minutes (Box Box 13)
  - correspondence to "leaders and specialists" (Box Box 14)
  - reading file Jan. - May 1987 (Box Box 14)
  - March 20th 1991 reception for Zelda Fichandler (Box Box 14)
  - 40th anniversary - lists and memos (Box Box 14)
  - 40th anniversary meetings (Box Box 14)
  - George's photo exhibit (Box Box 14)
  - 40th anniversary - chairman letters (Box Box 14)
  - book - Death of a Salesmen, text and criticism (Box Box 15)
  - Democracy and Esther, correspondence (Box Box 15)
  - Days of our Life, correspondence (Box Box 15)
  - Dead End Kids, handout (Box Box 15)
  - Dedan Kimathi, text and correspondence (Box Box 15)
  - Death of a Salesman, misc production material (Box Box 15)
  - Death of a Salesman, misc. materials (Box Box 15)
  - Death of a Salesman, Zelda's director's book (Box Box 15)
  - A Delicate Balance, misc. materials (Box Box 15)
  - A Delicate Balance, misc. info (Box Box 15)
  - Mister Johnson, correspondence (Box Box 16)
  - Miss Maragarida's Way (Box Box 16)
  - Miss Julie, program (Box Box 16)
  - Miss Ever's Boys (Box Box 16)
  - The Misanthrope, program and review (Box Box 16)
  - A Midsummers Night's Dream, misc. production materials (Box Box 16)
  - Mother of Courage, misc. materials (Box Box 16)
  - Morning's at Seven, program (Box Box 16)
  - Moon on a Rainbow Shawl, correspondence (Box Box 16)
  - A Moon for the Misbegotten, program and correspondence (Box Box 16)
  - Morocco, script (Box Box 16)
  - Moonchildren / Cancer, misc. correspondence and materials (Box Box 16)
  - The Mousetrap, program (Box Box 16)
  - Mrs. Murray's Farm, program (Box Box 16)
  - Mourning Becomes Electra, reviews (Box Box 16)
  - Motel, script (Box Box 16)
  - Mrs. Klein, misc. materials (Box Box 16)
  - Medal of Honor Rag - program (Box Box 17)
  - Mecca - correspondence (Box Box 17)
  - Measure for Measure - script, press release, notes (Box Box 17)
  - The Matchmaker - program and notes (Box Box 17)
  - Master Harold - script, program, notes (Box Box 17)
  - Mastergate - press clippings (Box Box 17)
  - Men in White - program (Box Box 17)
  - A Memory of 2 Mondays - program, press clips (Box Box 17)
  - A Man's a Man - program, news release (Box Box 17)
  - Mandragola - press release (Box Box 17)
  - The Man with a Load of Mischief - program, press release (Box Box 17)
  - Man with a Raincoat - script, notes (Box Box 17)
  - Man with a Raincoat - Playlab (Box Box 17)
  - Marie and Bruce - program (Box Box 17)
  - Marching Song - program (Box Box 17)
  - March of the Falsetts - press clippings (Box Box 17)
  - The Marathon - correspondence (Box Box 17)
  - Marat / Sade - program (Box Box 17)
  - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom - program (Box Box 17)
  - A Map of the World - program and correspondence (Box Box 17)
  - Master and Margarita - program, correspondence (Box Box 17)
  - The Master Builder - program (Box Box 17)
  - Mass Appeal - program (Box Box 17)
  - Mary Stuart - program, news clipping (Box Box 17)
  - Mary Barnes - news clippings (Box Box 17)
  - Marvin's Room - program (Box Box 17)
  - Marry me a Little - program (Box Box 17)
  - The Marriage of Bette and Boo - program (Box Box 17)
  - Melon - correspondence (Box Box 17)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream - news clippings (Box Box 17)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream - misc. notes (Box Box 18)
  - A Month in the Country - press clips (Box Box 18)
  - Monoploy - showcase (Box Box 18)
  - Money - correspondence, news clips (Box Box 18)
  - The Molly Maguires - programs (Box Box 18)
  - Moliere in Spite of Himself - program (Box Box 18)
  - Modigliani - press prints (Box Box 18)
  - Moby Dick - program (Box Box 18)
  - Much Ado About Nothing - program (Box Box 18)
  - Mrs. Warren's Profession - program (Box Box 18)
  - Moxie Malone - correspondence, script, misc. notes (Box Box 18)
  - Stephen Sondheim - press clips (Box Box 18)
  - George Furth - misc. notes (Box Box 18)
  - Merrily We Roll Along - press clippings (Box Box 18)
  - Merton of the Movies (Box Box 18)